# Sanju Raghuwanshi

https://www.linkedin.com/in/saniu-raghuwanshi/

Professional analyst with 5+ years of experience in data analysis & visualization to enhance business intelligence & deliver data-driven solutions ensuring the desired growth of business & organization. Experience writing scripts across various tools for predictive analysis and data-driven strategic planning.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Business Intelligence & Automation Specialist | Goldman Sachs | Nov 2018-Present

Tools used: Alteryx, Tableau, Python, REST API, SQL, Data warehousing

- Lead production-based SQL database migration resulting in 82% reduction in workflow runtimes, 95% reduction in skipped ETL workflow runs and saving 5 hours per day on maintenance
- Identified and collaborated with business stakeholders to create new risk metrics and nuanced reporting to better manage client default risk. Ultimately creating new operational workflows and fundamentally changing the way the revenue desk views risk
- Collaborated across 5 business units to better manage highly volatile products for 30+ trading desks
- Independently developed 6 Tableau dashboards receiving 600+ daily views highlighting open risk and maintained 30+ risk dashboards
- Created reporting to highlight market exposure risk, to inhibit client trading if thresholds are breached
- Manage book for work with center of excellence in Singapore, saving 20 hours of manual work per week
- Built SQL indexes and optimized SQL queries resulting in 60-70% fewer ETL workflow run times
- Contributed by leading and building Tableau dashboards for intracompany groups like Associate Advisory Group, Skills, and Collaboration pillar, Data School Foundation, Collective Community Collaboration, and DigiFest
- Supported critical regulatory & internal audits, and ad-hoc stakeholder data requirements by providing accurate data on time
- Actively participated in answering technical questions in Symphony chat rooms with 800+ members

## Strategic Data Architect | Goldman Sachs | Mar 2018-Oct 2018

Tools Used: Alteryx, Tableau, VBA, MS Access, MS Excel

- Identified production risks and created streamlined production tool to eliminate risks and improve impacted processes
- Structured and developed MS Access database to fulfill senior stakeholders and product expert's business requirements and preemptive needs for ad-hoc queries and predictive data analysis
- Automated 10+ functions extensively using VBA scripts to extract information from various Excel files and import them into MS Access in a particular fashion, saving 2 hours of daily manual work
- Engineered nuanced reporting to meet MiFID regulatory policies and avoid 1.5 hours of daily manual reporting
- Highly involved in UAT and regulatory testing. Responsible for writing test scripts and testing products across multiple systems

# Graduate BI Research and Teaching Assistant | Utah State University | Jan 2017-Apr 2017; Sep 2017-Dec 2017

Tools Used: SQL, Tableau, MS Powerpoint, Excel VBA

- Determined project scope, scheduled and executed the project on performance & grade analysis for Computer & Information Science departments allowing to determine the impact of online and offline classes on student learnings & performance
- Under the guidance of the professor, proficiently developed data visualization using Tableau with academic data processed in SQL giving insights on attendance & performance relationship
- Coordinated with multiple departments to develop research progress reports and visualization to publish in University bulletin
- Assisted lead manager with incoming requests for equipment maintenance & replacement for 5+ labs in the IT Department

#### Data Analyst Intern | Task Easy Inc. | May 2017-Aug 2017

**Tools Used**: Snowflake, SQL, Tableau, MS Powerpoint

- Successfully interpreted customer service data (ranging back to 3 years) to conclude managerial action and strategy
- Create interactive dashboards and reports using Tableau to improve strategies and operations
- Proposed solutions to improve system efficiencies which helped to reduce customer waiting time by 9.4%

## Data Analyst | Abhyudaya Multimedia, India | June 2015-July 2016

Tools Used: Excel, VBA, MS Powerpoint

- Performed data extraction and wrote queries to generate data aggregation for analysis & reporting
- Generated interactive charts from data originating from multiple sources
- Developed pivot tables with modification options, sorting & grouping functionality for chart view refresh and re-formation
- Wrote VBA automation script for data extraction and reporting, allowing to increase team efficiency by saving 2 hours daily

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Management Information Systems, GPA 3.5, Utah State University, December 2017

Bachelor of Engineering in Civil Engineering, GPA 3.8, Rajiv Gandhi Prodyogiki Vishwavidyalaya, Bhopal, India, July 2016

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Expert:** Alteryx, SQL, Tableau (certified Desktop Specialist), Power BI, Excel VBA, MS Access, JIRA, Agile project management, Data Modeling, MS Office

Proficient: Python, SSIS, SSIS, SSRS, MDX Query, Alloy data modeling, REST API